brighton.young@me.com

Summary

I am an exceptional fine dining and bar industry professional with vast working knowledge in all areas of the service industry. I have been well trained, with significant experience in leadership positions and management. I have front of house experience in craft cocktails, mixology, and bartending. I am customer focused, well-organized, efficient, and work well in a high pressure environment. I have a passion and talent for working with the public to personalize their experience with the establishment. My interest is in partnering with a fast paced, creative, and challenging environment to best utilize my expertise and talents.

Experience

Perry's Steakhouse
Austin, TX
Bartender
October 2016 to Present

Positions Held: Bartender, Banquet Bartender, Service Well Bartender, Server, Banquet Server, Cocktail Waitress

- Extensive experience serving the Community, Politicians, Celebrities, and Business Executives in one of Austin's premier fine dining locations.
- Developed training program and worked alongside corporate Mixologist/ Sommelier team to correctly execute and present new seasonal cocktails to the staff.
- Received high recognition for multiple perfect scores from Secret Shoppers, numerous rave Yelp, Open Table, and Trip Advisor reviews, and personalized endorsements from guests.
- Created a complimentary full time bar team with an organized management schedule.
- Excelled as a team member in a high volume, fast paced performance based environment while giving guests an exceptional experience.

Truluck's Crab & Steakhouse

Austin, TX

Bartender April 2015 to October 2016

Positions Held: Bartender, Banquet Bartender, Service Well Bartender, Server, Banquet Server, Cocktail Waitress

- Recognized for being in the Top 20% of Truluck's employees based off performance, Nationwide
- On-site coordinator and directed execution for wedding rehearsals, anniversaries, and other large special events.
- Training and testing for seasonal food, promotions, and delicacies.
- Extensive experience serving the Community, Politicians, Celebrities, and Business Executives in one of Austin's premier fine dining locations
- Managed and staffed front of house and service bar

Sullivan's Steakhouse

Austin, TX

Sommelier

April 2013 to April 2015

Positions Held: Sommelier, Shift Leader, Bartender, Server, Banquet Captain, Cocktail Waitress

- Wine Assistant Manager, engaged and educated guests in selection of personal wine choices.
- Organized and kept inventory records of all wine, beer, and liquor in the restaurant. Performed weekly wine tastings and classes with the staff to educate them on our wine list.
- As a shift lead I was in charge of staff schedules based on business needs.
- Trained and managed workers in each department, achieved significant improvements in their productivity

Sullivan's Steakhouse (continued) Sommelier

Austin, TX
April 2013 to April 2015

- Executed managerial paperwork, security, cleanliness, and orders for next business day.
- Trained and managed various workers in each department, achieved significant improvements in team productivity.
- Investigated and resolved customer complaints about food quality or service.
- Provided personalized service to large groups and VIP customers.

Soleil at Lake Travis

Server Trainer

Austin, TX

May 2011 to April 2013

- Supervised preparation of meals and beverages for customers.
- Coordinated activities between kitchen, dining room, and banquet operations.
- Trained hostesses and servers to company expectations.
- Motivated employees to work as a team and provided one-on-one training to key personnel.
- Executed daily operations of required set ups, stocking, and related duties.
- Ensured customer satisfaction with their dining experience.

Roy's Hawaiian Fusion Hostess; Stocker

Chicago, IL

March 2011 to May 2012

- Executed daily operations of stocking wherever needed.
- Coordinated and planned daily customer seating for customer time efficiency.
- Worked closely with management and staff for full occupancy reservations.

Education

Columbia College Chicago
Major Dance, Minor Marketing

Chicago, IL

2012

Northwest Arkansas Academy of Fine Arts High School Degree Rogers, AR

2010

Additional Training:

- Management Development Program with Sullivan's Steakhouse
- Personal Assistant for Professionals
- Level 1 Wine Sommelier
- · Working on Wine Sommelier Level 2
- Restaurant Software Knowledge & Training

Awards:

- Top 20% Performance Based Award (Truluck's Nationwide)
- National Society of Collegiate Scholars
- Dean's List both years at Columbia College
- Columbia College Honor's Program

Licenses:

- Texas Alcohol & Beverage Commission (TABC) certified
- Food Handler's Certification in Texas
- Licensed Insurance Agent in the State of Texas
- Certified Trainer with Sullivan's Steakhouse

References Available Upon Request